每天下午我都去盧克的學校
Every afternoon, I've been going to Luke's campus
幫他為橄欖球選拔賽做訓練
to help him train for rugby tryouts.
我們再練最后一遍舉人爭球怎么樣
What do you say we practice that lineout lift one last time?
-來... -我得走了
- And... - I got to go.
我可不想耽誤了女性研究課[時間]
I don't want to be late for women's studies.
我都是這么叫我的午休時間
That's what I call my lunch break.
好吧
All right.
祝你選拔會好運
Good luck at tryouts.
前幾天
The other day,
有個很有意思的東西吸引了我的目光
something pretty interesting caught my eye.
為了使微觀經濟過程
modifications must be made
與供求分析相符
to standard microeconomic procedures
需要做出一些修正
to apply supply and demand analysis.
首先 我們構建一個效用函數
First, we construct a utility function,
這里Y軸表示收入
where Y equals income
X軸表示服務的成本
and X equals the cost of services.
這個嘛
Well...
接下來 我們要么改變X
Uh, next, we vary either X --
什么 你有什么高見
What -- What's on your mind?
恕我直言
Well, um, with all due respect,
這有滿滿一房間有抱負的房地產經紀人
uh, you have a roomful of aspiring Realtors here,
我擔心你可能用這堆數字公式
and I worry that you might be turning them off
毀了他們的興趣
with all those numbers and formulas.
這可是一項激動人心的事業
It's actually a very exciting business.
是一項跟人與情感
It's about people and -- and emotional connections
還有印了你肖像的磁鐵息息相關的事業
and magnets with your face on them.
你覺得你能大搖大擺走進來
You think you can just walk in here
然后開始教課嗎
and start teaching this class?
對不起 我不應該
I'm so sorry. I shouldn't have --
不 我是在問你 你能替我教這個嗎
No, I'm asking -- can you teach this class for me?
要是我現在走 停車費會劃算許多
If I leave now, I won't have to pay the all-day parking rate.
跟院長談了十分鐘
10 minutes with the dean,
結果發現 我曾賣給他一間房
who, it turns out, I'd sold a house to,
現在我正式入職了
and I was official.
想象一下菲爾·鄧菲
Imagine Phil Dunphy shaping minds
在神圣的紅衫社區大學
in the hallowed halls of Sequoia Community College,
這建校長達兩年的大學教書
established 2016.
大家能看到這個表格
As you can see from this graph,
不是關于X和Y的
it's not about X's and Y's.
而是關于嘿和哈的
It's about oohs and ahs.
好
Mm. Okay.
那么 房地產等于什么呢
So, what does real estate equal?
眼神交流
eye contact.
好了 你的早餐快準備好了
All right. Your breakfast is almost ready.
你今天庭審需要多吃點攢足力氣
You're gonna need all your energy for the courtroom today
以防你得放聲呼號"是我不守規矩嗎
in case you have to yell, "I'm out of order?
是你無視規則
You're out of order.
是這該死的體制一塌糊涂"
The whole damn system's out of order!"
估計不會
Might not do that.
我覺得會贏 所以現在是這體制的鐵粉
I think I'm winning, so big fan of the system right now.
-反正讓我這個前輩 -小卡
- Anyway, it can't hurt - Cam.
看一眼這個案子又沒什么壞處
to have some experienced eyes take a look at this police work.
馬馬虎虎 無聊 沒意思
Sloppy. Sloppy, sloppy.
行了 我知道你自命什么名偵探
Okay, I know you fancy yourself some sort of detective.
你知道嗎 我小時候就是個業余小偵探呢
You know, I was quite the amateur sleuth as a boy,
現實生活中的百科全書
a real-life Encyclopedia Brown.
大家都叫我知識索引瓊斯
They called me Thesaurus Jones.
我現在真的需要安靜一會兒
What I really need right now is just a few minutes of silence,
比如 要我說最難的案子
just like -- I would say my toughest case
那得是"消失的雪人之謎"
was "The Case of the Missing Snowman."
一開始 我以為他活過來了
You know, at first, I thought he'd come to life,
-結果 -噓 在講我的庭審
- but turns out - Oh. Shh! My trial!
今天是地檢進行證人問詢的第四天
Today marks the fourth day of witness questioning by the DA's office.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
那是你嗎
Is that you?
我看上去像一個小精靈剛剛走進了
I look like an elf that just walked
自己的驚喜派對
into his own surprise party.
不 像我們倆那次用微波爐熱的南瓜
No, it's like the time we tried to microwave a squash.
我 這可是我的第一次大型庭審
I -- Okay, this is my first big trial,
一個 一個讓我名聲大噪的機會
a-a chance to make a name for myself.
現在所有人會討論的都是這張丑畫了
All anyone's gonna be talking about is that awful picture!
這簡直是場災難
Okay, this is a disaster.
市中心有個地方
Th-- There's a place downtown
所有的律師都在那喝酒
where all the lawyers go to drink.
叫旁廳酒吧
It's called The Side Bar.
他們把每一個人首次大型庭審的
They put courtroom sketches on the wall
素描畫掛在墻上
of everyone's first big trial.
可能沒人看到呢
Maybe nobody saw it.
未必是壞事 說不定只是安珀警報呢
Don't assume the worst. It could just be an Amber Alert.
-老爸好 -在呢
- Hey, Dad. - Yo.
既然這是我們第一天和新的合作伙伴見面
Since it's our first day with our new partners,
我覺得你這次上班是不是
I thought maybe you could get to work
能盡量準時
as close to on time as poss--
我盡量
I will try my best.
大家好
Hi.
不好意思 我遲到了嗎
I'm sorry. Am I late?
沒有 沒有 沒 沒
No, no, no, no. Oh.
我們對時間要求沒那么嚴格
And we're not real time sticklers here. Ah.
我們發現員工按照自己的節奏工作
We've found that team members really excel
能事半功倍
when they follow their own energy rhythms.
有點意思 因為我發現
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Interesting, 'cause I've found
員工們在公司還沒倒閉之前
team members are happiest
才是最高興的
when the company stays in business,
也就是說9點前到崗
which means asses in chairs by 9:00.
爸 你能跟我出來一小會嗎
Dad, could I just have a quick -- quick sec with you?
行啊
Sure.
是這樣的 爸 你看
Um...so, Dad, look,
這里的公司文化不一樣
the culture is just different here.
你不能帶著打壓的態度進去
And you just can't come in with a sledgehammer,
不然氣氛會很緊張
or it's gonna create tension.
你不想讓他們疏遠你吧
You don't want to alienate people.
-所以你想讓我改變真我 -不是
- So you want me to change who I am? - No.
我想讓你先把真我收起來
I just want you to hide who you are.
我是說 來 就改變一點
I mean, come on. Just a little bit.
把這個摘了
Let's get rid of this.
看看 這就好多了
Look at that. That's better already.
這個50出頭的帥大叔是誰呀
Who is this 50-something, huh?
-行吧 我努力好好表現 -謝謝 老爸
-Fine. I will be on my best behavior. -Thanks, Dad.
剛剛真不好意思
So sorry about that.
沒關系
Well, it's no problem.
-和家人的時光很重要嘛 -是的
- Family time is so important. - Uh-huh.
所以我們給爸爸們提供14個月的帶薪陪產假
That's why we offer 14 months paid paternity leave.
我們來看一下那個無限纖薄模型的最新進展
Let's see an update on that Thinfinity model.
設計很酷啊
Ooh. Cool design.
-我跟誰來擊個掌 -大家
- Who do I high-five for that, huh? - Everybody.
我們的設計會議就是走噴涌爆發風
Our design meetings are organized around burstiness,
是一個急速創作的過程
which is a rapid-fire creative process
靠的就是解鎖潛意識的奇思妙想
that really just unlocks the unconscious.
沒人覺得那個很分心嗎
Does anybody else find that distracting?
事實上 那對刺激左腦有好處
Actually, it's great for left-brain stimulation.
贏家肯定是我
I got winner!
我們不計分
We don't keep score.
-不計嗎 -小心
- No? - Watch out!
什么鬼
What the hell?!
你不知道太空球嗎
You don't know about Zorbing?
能促進身體和大腦的平衡
It promotes mind/body balance.
是從德國的類似項目學的
It's kind of like the German version of Flerming.
行了 夠了
Okay, that's it.
現在 我要教教你們
Now, I'm about to introduce you squids
什么叫做
to a little thing called
鞠躬盡瘁外加心力交瘁的辛勤工作
back-breaking, soul-crushing hard work.
你們這里過去五年有多少人犯過心臟病
How many heart attacks have you had here in the last five years?
一次都沒有嗎 我這是在哪
Zero? Where am I?!
美國人熱愛衣柜
America loves closets,
我是來造衣柜的 媽的
and I'm here to build them, damn it!
等我看到每早有人上班前先在車里痛哭時
And you get this back when I see people pull up in the morning
我再把乒乓球還給你們
crying in their cars.
對
Yeah.
你非得這樣嗎
Okay, must you?
我們一定要
You know what, we are gonna make sure
讓那個素描專家看到你最帥氣的一面
that sketch artist sees the best possible version of you.
掐掐蘋果肌 臉色會更紅潤
Let's get those apples a-shining!
好了 住手 別掐了
Okay, okay, stop. Don't!
你發"O"音時臉會變得很奇怪
Okay, your face gets weird when you make that "O" sound,
別發這個音
so avoid that.
你認真的嗎
A-Are you serious?
被告管理的是含4個"O"音開頭的
The defendant runs the Orange County
橘子郡海洋與鳥類組織
Oceanic and Ornithological Organization.
-畫面太驚悚我不忍看 -什么
- That was hard to watch. - Wha--
全體起立
All rise.
最后整理一下
Last looks.
坐下
Be seated.
普里契特先生 你可以繼續詢問證人了
Mr. Pritchett, you may resume your questioning of the witness.
好的
Okay.
米奇爾 米奇爾 他來了
Mitchell. Mitchell. He's here.
用你最好看的角度對著他
Only give him your best side.
別讓日光燈直射你 別發"O"音
Avoid the fluorescent lights, no O's,
無論你做什么 都千萬別站到那個法警旁邊
and whatever you do, do not stand next to the bailiff.
他帥得令人窒息
He is breathtaking!
真的好帥
Oh, my God.
律師
Counselor?
抱歉 法官大人
Uh, sorry, Your Honor. Um...
-卡彭特小姐... -丑臉警告
- Miss Carpenter... - Bad side!
你在案發當晚
...do you recall seeing this man
有否見過這個男人
on the night in question?
見過 先生
Yes, sir.
據你所知 他是不是
And is he, to your knowledge, the C.E.O...
橘子郡海洋與鳥類組織的總裁
of the Orange County Oceanic and Ornithological Organization?
律師 你說話很含糊
Counselor, you're mumbling.
請你重復一遍問題
Can you repeat that, please?
他是不是負責管理那個鳥和水的地方
Does he run the bird and water place?
是的
He does.
他今天是否在...
And is he here today in this, uh...
-我剛剛問... -再過來一點
- As I was saying... - Little further.
他今天是否
...is he here today in this,
在法庭內
uh -- in this courtroom?
那個就是他
That's him.
請注意 我很肯定
Let the court note that I am pretty sure
證人已經指認出了被告
that the witness has identified the defendant.
肘部有補丁
Elbow patches?
你是不是又在鐵板燒餐廳燒壞了外套
Did you burn through another blazer at Benihana's?
其實是特地為新工作準備的
Actually, it is for my new position
我要去你學校教房地產課
teaching real estate at your school.
你在說什么
What are you talking about?
他們給了我一份工作
They offered me a job.
不過 聽我說
But hey, listen -- listen to me.
先不說這是我的畢生夢想
Lifelong dreams aside,
還要先征求你同意 我才會接受這份工作
I'm not taking this unless you're on board.
我絕對不同意
I'm definitely not.
我懂
I get it.
你不希望被自己老爸破壞了形象
Don't want your old Pops cramping your style,
所以我不去了
so I'm -- I'm out.
說來好笑
It's just funny.
我都不記得上次這么興奮是幾時的事了
Can't remember the last time I was this excited.
但除非你也為此興奮
But it wouldn't -- wouldn't make any sense
否則這事就沒意思了
unless you were excited, too.
我的內心沒有一絲波瀾
Not even a little bit.
好吧
Right.
不過那些孩子真可憐
Those poor kids, though, huh?
我有那么多知識可以教給他們
I have so much to offer.
比如說
For example,
銷售不同風格的房屋時應分別搭配哪些餅干
which house styles are sold by which cookie type?
法國折衷主義風格
French Revival --
搭配馬卡龍
Macaroons.
英國都鐸風格
English Tudor --
搭配牛油酥餅
shortbread.
但 我明白你的想法
But... we both know what you want,
所以我會辭職
so, uh, I'll resign and go back
繼續思考我退休前的年頭可以做些什么
to trying to figure out what to do with my final years.
好
Okay.
我需要找個地方借住幾天
I need a place to stay for a couple of days.
不能回家 也不能去學校
Can't go home, can't go to school,
我也不想談論這事
don't want to talk about it.
知道了
Got it.
我知道艾麗克斯很想聊這事
I knew that Alex wanted to talk about it,
但我自己也有一堆煩心事
but I had a lot on my mind.
今早喬讓我很頭疼
I had a rough morning with Joe.
第一天上學愉快哦
Have a great first day.
你不送我進去嗎
Aren't you gonna walk me in?
不送 一年級學生都定點下車自己走進去的
No. In first grade, you have drop-off.
沒人說過有這件事啊
No one said anything about drop-off.
要是我找不到我放東西的格子怎么辦
What if I can't find my cubby?
學校沒有小格子 只有儲物柜
They don't have cubbies. They have lockers here.
等一下 等一下 我的午餐盒呢
Wait. Wait a second. Where's my lunchbox?
我幫你申請了在學校用餐
Oh, I signed you up for the hot-lunch program.
這里到底是什么鬼地方
What is this place?
我最近有些壓力
Okay, I've been feeling some pressure
不知道今年畢業后該做什么
about what to do after I graduate this year,
我爸媽又一直問個不停
and my parents are constantly asking me about it.
你不是打算工作嗎
I thought that you were going to work.
我本來也這么想 但最近我質疑一切
So did I, but lately, I've been questioning everything.
我甚至考慮要當研究生[男人]
I even thought about becoming a fellow.
艾麗克斯 這可是巨大的改變
Ay, Alex, that's a big change.
但至少你的名字通用
But at least you get to keep the same name.
我都不確定我是否真想這么做
I'm not even sure it's what I really want.
你得考慮清楚了
Okay, you have to be very sure,
因為我聽說要變回去更難
because I heard it's even harder to reverse it.
我們能聊點別的嗎 喬人呢
Can we talk about anything else? Where's Joe?
他今天開始上小學
He started school today.
我在校門口放他下車時 他很慌
He was so panicky when I dropped him off.
我不知道為什么 不過是一年級而已嘛
I don't know why. It's just first grade.
不過是一年級而已
Just first grade?!
壓力就是從那時開始的
That's when the pressure starts!
你要嚇死人家啦
Ay! You're freaking me out!
艾麗克斯以后會是一個神經質的男人
Alex is going to be a very nervous man.
不好意思 畫素描的
Uh, e-excuse me, sketch man.
-我們想跟你聊聊你的畫 -對
- We'd like a word with you about your little drawings. - Yes.
你們不記得我了 對吧
You don't remember me, do you?
你是...
It's -- Um...
很明顯我們得罪過你
Well, obviously, we have offended you somehow.
你是我們害你被炒魷魚的咖啡師 對嗎
Oh, were you the barista we had fired?
給你們個提示 我租過你們家樓上的房間
Here's a hint -- I once stayed in your upstairs rental.
誰會用光一整籃迎賓用品啊
Who consumes an entire welcome basket?
我們通常有一半能重復使用
We usually reuse half this stuff.
薄荷糖都吃光了 他不過住了一晚而已
All the Altoids. He was here one night.
連辣根芥末醬都吃完了
He -- He even ate the horseradish mustard.
他都拿來蘸什么吃了
What did he put it on?
我們故意沒提供餅干啊
We purposely don't give crackers.
很抱歉我們如此失禮 可是
We are so sorry we offended you, but --
道歉來不及了
Ooh, too late.
你倆任我魚肉
I own you two.
我還沒用上大絕招呢
And I haven't even gotten to my best stuff yet.
我還可以把你畫得更紅
I can go redder.
你不會的
You wouldn't.
等我把你畫成一字眉你就知道厲害了
Just wait till I connect the brows.
求你善良
Please.
我們還有個孩子
We have a child.
有意思了 CNN臺的記者
Oh, fun -- a reporter from CNN.
看來這幅畫像就要被全國人民看到了
Looks like this pretty little portrait's about to go national.
我們該怎么辦
Uh... What-what are we gonna do?
只有我這么想嗎 聽起來
Okay, is it just me, or does this sound
-該知識索引瓊斯登場了 -只有你
- like a job for Thesaurus Jones? - It's just you.
不 我指黒函威脅他 米奇爾
No. Blackmail, Mitchell!
我們得挖點這個人的黑料
We just have to dig something up on this guy.
應該問題不大 因為每個人
Shouldn't be a problem, because everyone's
都有想藏的秘密
hiding something.
每個人
Everyone.
我感覺你還想再說一次
I feel like you're sitting on one more...
-每個人 -沒錯
- Everyone. - Yep.
我害怕的事發生了
Just as I feared,
我爸碾壓了辦公室所有人的精氣神
my dad had crushed the spirit of everyone in that office.
我必須想辦法證明
I had to do something to prove
我們不是古板的掃興鬼
we weren't some stuffy killjoys.
是時候放出派對克萊爾了
It was time to bust out Party Claire.
89年春假后她引退了
She'd retired after spring break '89.
92年又引退了一次
And again in '92.
你有時間嗎
Hey, do you have a second?
如果你想說我不尊重你們的方法
If this is about my respecting your process --
其實我們想謝謝你之前立威
Actually, we want to thank you for laying down the law before.
因為我們作為一個公司已經沒樣子了
Because we have gone soft as a company,
我們需要幾個成熟的人加入
we needed a couple grown-ups to come in
讓我們重回正軌
and put us back on track.
多虧了你
You know, thanks to you,
我們那些分散注意力的東西都撤走了
we've gotten rid of all the distractions --
乒乓球桌和水槍都撤走了
no more ping-pong tables, squirt guns.
我們唯一沒找到的是那個巨大的...
The only thing we couldn't find was that giant --
休息時間 賤人們
Break time, bitches!
原來這有點...
Uh, it turns out this is a little --
我的天 無限纖薄模型
Oh, my God! The Thinfinity!
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry!
我的天 太對不起了
Oh, my God! I'm so sorry!
我...
I -- Oh!
對不起
Sorry.
畫畫那小子也保養得太好了
Sketch boy was unusually well-groomed
政府補貼的健身房不可能有這效果
for somebody coming out of a government-subsidized gym.
其中肯定有貓膩
Something wasn't right.
知識索引瓊斯的鼻子聞出來了
I was getting that old Thesaurus Jones tingle.
我決定四處嗅探一下
I decided to do some sniffing around.
那畫畫的臉上有種光彩
Sketch guy's face had a kind of glow
只有用了昂貴的潤膚霜才會有
that can only be achieved with expensive creams and unguents,
而我只找到了幾包廉價的通用乳液
yet all I found were packets of cut-rate all-purpose lotions.
根據我的信息源 健身房有個領導樓層
According to my sources, the gym had an executive level
能提供各種高級水療護膚品
that provides all manner of fancy spa products,
但只有法官和律師才能加入
but it's for judges and attorneys only.
我聲東擊西 告訴保全人員
I created a diversion by convincing the security detail
毛巾出了些緊急狀況
there was a towel emergency...
There's a towel emergency.
并黑進了健身房的電腦系統
...and hacked into the gym's computer system.
原來他一直在偷偷進入領導層
Turns out he's been accessing the executive level
靠的是盜刷
by swiping the ID
一位退休法官 維克多·格雷厄姆的卡
of one Victor Graham, a retired judge.
各位陪審員
Members of the jury,
被告凱恩先生想讓你們認為
the defendant, Mr. Kane, would have you believe
在罪案發生時他正在工作
that he was working at the time of the crime.
光頭[大膽]
Bald?!
厚顏的謊言
...faced lies!
律師
Counselor?
因為證據明顯表明
Because evidence would clearly suggest that, um...
盡管詹姆斯·凱恩
...that while James Kane
的確在他公司的領導樓層有間辦公室
does have an office on his company's executive floor,
那晚他根本就沒有去
he was nowhere near it that night.
想得美 領導層詹姆[健身房]
Nice try, executive-level Jim.
凱恩
...Kane,
可我們盯上你了
but we're onto you.
女士們先生們 在你們退庭[退休]前
Ladies and gentlemen, before you've retired,
自己判斷[法官]
judge...for yourself
繪制一幅更切實的結論圖
and draw a more accurate conclusion
比凱恩先生想讓你們相信的話更切實
than the one Mr. Kane would have you believe...
律師 你說的話很奇怪
Counselor, you're speaking weirdly.
我肯定你們會發現被告的不在場證明
I'm sure you will find the defendant's alibi
非常不可信[苗條]
to be thin.
甚至更不可信[苗條]
Even thinner.
謝謝你
Thank you.
下午好 年輕的房地產經紀人們
Good afternoon, young realtors.
下課后我有重要事情宣布
I have a very important announcement to make after class,
在那之前
but in the meantime,
請你們配合地打開書本
if you would be so kind as to open your books --
老天 我做不到
Oh, boy. I can't do this.
同學們 今天是我們最后一天一起上課了
Students, today is our last day together.
我很珍視我們在一起的時間
I've treasured our time together.
布雷特 我知道我們最開始有點矛盾
Brett, I know we got off to a rough start,
但當我們消除那些隔閡后
but once we broke down those walls,
我都不知道誰教了對方更多
I'm not sure who was teaching who.
惠特尼 你是我所認識最堅強的單身母親
Whitney, you're the toughest single mother I know.
露西 對你媽好一些
Lucy, you be good to your mom.
包包 你與閱讀障礙抗爭太了不起了
Bob, amazing how you battle that dyslexia.
不過你或許不該再對父母那么憤怒
Maybe ease off on the anger toward your parents, though.
他們給你起的名字給你省了很多麻煩
They did you a solid giving you that name.
我們會想您的 爾菲老師
We're gonna miss you, Mr. Nudphy.
你又說反了 不過
It's -- You -- You -- You flipped it, but...
我也會想你們的
I'm gonna miss you guys, too.
地段 地段 地段
Location. Location. Location.
你記住了
You memorized it.
第二次也是最后一次
Now, for the second and last time...
下課
class dismissed.
爸
Dad.
盧克
Luke?
你在教室后面多久了
How long have you been back there?
我基本上看到了一切
I pretty much saw the whole thing.
-爸 -怎么
- Hey, Dad? - Yeah?
別忘了你的咖啡杯
Don't forget your coffee mug.
我相信這是最好的結果
I'm sure this all worked out for the best.
我或許會想念
I'll, uh, probably miss
一些隨性的扔飛盤的機會
a few spontaneous Frisbee opportunities and...
顯然還有翻跟頭交換生項目
apparently, a tumbling exchange program --
好吧 還有業余發明家協會
oh, well -- and an Amateur Inventors Association.
反正改變世界八成也沒什么意思
How much fun could it be changing the world, anyway?
"紅杉大學選手為您呈現
"The Sequoia College Players Present:
霍爾與奧茲魔術表演"
A Hall and Oates Magic Show."
-爸 等等 -怎么 盧克
- Dad, wait. - Yes, Luke?
這次也別忘了咖啡杯
Don't forget your mug again.
拜托
Come on!
你看不出我來這是命中注定嗎
Can't you see I'm meant to be here?
抱歉 只是我從來沒獨自上過學
I'm sorry, but I've never had a school to myself.
過去我總是艾麗克斯的傻弟弟
I was always Alex's dumb brother
或曼尼的性感侄子
or Manny's hot nephew.
現在我終于能做自己了
Now I can finally be my own person.
抱歉 我理解
I'm sorry. I get it.
我真的理解
I-I r-I-I really do.
我想我只是興奮過頭了
I think I was just getting a little overexcited.
我
I'll, uh...
我們家里見
I'll see you at home.
鄧菲
Dunphy.
真高興撞見你了 我想當面恭喜你
Glad I ran into you so I can congratulate you personally.
等等 我入選球隊了嗎
Wait. I made the team?
先發球員
First string.
不得不說 你舉人爭球的姿勢一看就是練家子
I got to say, your form on that lineout lift was impeccable.
-謝謝 -是啊
- Thanks. - Yeah.
爸 我入選球隊了
Hey, Dad. I made the team.
太棒了
That's amazing!
我就知道你會入選 你是天生好手
I knew you would. You're a natural.
我有個很好的老師
Well, I had a great teacher.
你聽我說
So, listen.
校區挺大的
This is a big campus.
或許我們可以在此共存
Maybe we could both be here
只要我們保證不在對方面前晃悠
if we promise to stay out of each other's way.
我很不想踩進你的地盤的
Well, I'd hate to step on your toes.
不會 你不會
No, no, y-you wouldn't.
我也不想阻止你
I would hate to stop you
去做一些你很擅長的事情
from doing something you're so good at.
我可以考慮考慮
I guess I could think about it.
其實我也不是整天都泡在這里
I mean, it's not like I'd be there all the time.
畢竟我得上課 還得上班
I, uh, have class and office hours,
我每周二四的早上11點到下午2點
and I have the 11:00 A.M. to 2:00 P.M. slot
也得負責搞校園電臺的事情
at the campus radio station on Tuesdays and Thursdays.
如果你想當我的助手...
Hey, if you want to be my sidekick...
-老爸 -你說得對
- Dad? - You're right.
最好還是我獨自為節目發聲吧
It's better if I do all the voices.
怎么著
What's up?!
這些是什么
What's all this?
你讓我好緊張喬今天會不開心
Well, you got me so nervous about Joe's terrible day
我就先把這些擺出來好哄他開心
that I put all this out to cheer him up --
圣代 電子游戲
sundae, video game.
我還給他寫了段鼓舞的話
I even wrote him a little pep talk.
我們能活在藥品的黃金時期真是太好了
We're lucky to live in the golden age of medicines.
外公 我要在這里住幾天
Hey, Grandpa, I'm staying here for a couple of days,
我也不想聊到底為什么
and I do not want to talk about it.
行
Cool.
喬回來了
That's Joe.
我老爸在家嗎
Hey, is my dad home?
靠 我媽來這里干嘛
Crap. What is my mom doing here?
跟我來
Come with me.
我欠他一句抱歉
I owe him an apology.
我在公司給他出了大丑
I made a huge scene at work.
有時候跟人道歉的最好方法
Well, sometimes the best way to say "I'm sorry"
就是通過電郵
is in an e-mail.
你何不寫封道歉函到"杰的電腦郵件@aol.com"呢
Why don't you write him at JaysComputerMail@aol.com?
我用一個巨型倉鼠球碾了一群人
I plowed over a bunch of people in a giant hamster ball.
然后我試著討好公司里的美食粉
And then I tried to impress the foodies
所以點了印度菜當午餐
by ordering Indian for lunch.
而為了去掉我口中的
And then I chewed some gum
香菜味 我嚼了口香糖
to get rid of my coriander breath,
我挺確定現在粘到我頭發上了
and I'm pretty sure some's in my hair.
接著我...
And then I -- Oh --
被絆倒然后把膝蓋跌破皮了
tripped and fell and skinned my knee,
而且還讓大家看到了我的內褲
and everybody saw my underwear.
牛逼爆了
Crushed it!
只要人酷 第一天上學簡直太簡單了
First days are easy when you're cool.
但我有點可憐康納·B同學
I do feel bad for Conner B.
他帶的雞蛋沙拉午餐都臭了
He brought stinky egg salad for lunch.
他以后只能去找護士阿姨吃飯了
He's gonna have to eat with the nurse.
天啊
Oh, God! Ay.
喬 你先上樓待著吧
Uh, Joe, why don't you go upstairs?
我只想回到我以前的公司
I just want to go back to my old office,
我在那里有朋友
where I had friends.
我理解
I know.
有時候...
Sometimes...
我們都有不順的日子
...you know, we all have bad days.
而...
And...
而有時候我們得... 面對壞男生
And sometimes, we have to -- to deal with mean boys.
臭男生最壞了
Boys are mean.
你說得對 歌洛莉亞
You're right, Gloria.
我說得對啊
I am right?
你知道我最愛這個家庭什么嗎
Oh, you know what I love about this family?
我們永不退縮 尤其是你
We're not quitters -- especially you.
還記得你當時學游泳碰到了多少困難嗎
Remember how hard it was for you to learn how to swim?
的確很難
It was hard.
但現在它是你最愛的一項事物
But now it's your favorite thing in the world
因為它能讓你意識到自己多強大
because it reminds you of how strong you are.
我的確是喜歡游泳啦 但...
I mean, I like to swim...
觸底就會反彈 明天只會更好
Tomorrow can only be better.
但為了以防萬一 我午餐時間會來
But just in case, I'll come at lunch,
我會隔著圍欄親親你的小臉
and I will kiss you through the fence.
我大概11點給你發消息
How about I text you around 11:00
告訴你我的情況好不好如何
and let you know how I'm doing?
你想告訴我為什么要躲著你媽媽嗎
So, you want to tell me why you're avoiding your mom?
我沒有在躲她
I'm not avoiding her.
這... 這些是什么啊
Hey, what's -- what's all this?
危險奧沙哥的紀念品 我是個瘋狂收藏家
Danger O'Shea memorabilia. I'm a big collector.
誰是危險奧沙哥啊
Who's Danger O'Shea?
傳說中的大膽王
Legendary daredevil.
以騎著摩托車飛越學校大巴而出名
Got famous for jumping over a school bus on his motorcycle.
過來 跟我談談
Get over here! Talk to me.
告訴我你為什么在躲你媽
Tell me why you're avoiding your mom.
好吧
Okay.
我這一輩子都在走科研的道路
Well, I've been on a science track my whole life,
我父母也很喜歡 咱家的"科學家艾麗克斯"
which my parents love -- "Alex the scientist."
但最近... 我心里有些別的的想法
But...lately, I've been having second thoughts.
我一直很愛唱歌 而最近我也去了
I've always loved singing, and -- and I've been doing
開麥之夜嘗試了表演
some open-mic nights recently,
反饋還真的挺不錯的
and it's been going really well.
我明白你想說的了 唱給我聽
I see where this is going. Sing for me.
什么 現在嗎
What, like...right now?
你就唱吧
Just sing.
? 在彩虹之上的某處 ?
♪ Somewhere over the rainbow ♪
Over the rainbow
? 天空很藍 ?
♪ Skies are blue ♪
很棒呢
That was great.
好好做科研
Stick to science.
你家的人可真是懂怎么鼓勵人呢
Wow. You really got a knack for pep talks in this house.
我不是說你肯定不行
I'm not saying it's impossible.
我只是讓你賭贏面大的
I'm saying play the odds.
舉例來說 比如那個奧沙哥
For example, you take this O'Shea guy.
棒棒噠 又回到了他上面
Oh, good. We're back to him.
他不要命但是聰明
But he was smart.
他創立了一家公司 站穩了腳步
He started a business, got established.
當他發現自己還是想去追搏命的夢想
And when he couldn't kick the daredevil dream,
他就去了
he went for it.
他真的很厲害 超強
And he was good -- real good --
直到滑鐵盧的那天 他試著
until that fateful day he tried to jump
開學校大巴飛越過摩托車
over a motorcycle in a school bus.
幸好 雖然特技沒成功
Fortunately for him, unlike his act,
可是他有個安全保障
he had a safety net.
-他的生意 -立刻回到商場上
- His business. - Jumped right back in.
不到一年 生意超越了頂峰
Within a year, it was bigger than ever.
我想說的是 你已經走這條科研道路15年了
The point is, you've been on the science track for 15 years.
走完它嘛 為自己打好基礎
See it through. Build a foundation.
如果過幾年你還忍不住想唱
If in a couple of years, you still have the singing bug,
大膽去啊
go for it!
我想你說得對
I guess you're right.
我如果真的放棄現在這條路
It would be pretty dumb of me
那其實還挺蠢的呢
to give up on the career path I'm on.
我畢業后的第一年就能掙50萬呢
I could make half a mil my first year out of school.
那同職的男人薪水會是多少呢
Wow! What do they pay men?
那危險哥還有再嘗試做過特技嗎
So, Danger never did another stunt again?
他做任何事都還是帶著那特立獨行的精神
He still brings that maverick spirit to everything he does,
這也是為何他能在業界封王
which is why he got to the top of his industry.
有些人覺得那才是他最牛逼的一個特技
Some people think it's the greatest stunt he ever pulled off.
謝謝你的一番話
Thanks for the talk...
危險哥
Danger.
所以我贏了那案子 而更好的是
So, I won my case, and even better,
這圖會被掛到旁廳酒吧
this is going up at The Side Bar. Yeah.
或許你現在會對我的
And now maybe you'll have some respect
偵查技能有所尊重
for my investigative skills.
其實是挺簡單的一個案子 如同我所說
It was a pretty simple case, because, as I've said,
每個人都有想藏的秘密
everyone has something to hide.
每個人
everyone